Watch Movies, TV Series & Live Sports www.admitme.app
Apóyanos y conviértete en miembro VIP Para eliminar todos los anuncios www.OpenSubtitles.org
Captain.
Capitán.
Thanks, Captain.
Gracias, capitán.
Hold on.
Un momento.
Hold on, hold on.
Espere, espere.
Right, bring him to. Come on, hurry up! Hurry up.
Bien, tráiganlo. Vamos, ¡apresúrense! Rápido.
All right, all right. Bring him over here.
Bueno, está bien. Colóquenlo aquí.
Come on, line him up, line him up, line him up.
Vamos, alinéenlo, alinéenlo, alinéenlo.
One, two, three, come on. Bring him over.
Uno, dos, tres, vamos. Acérquenlo.
Hello, sir. My name is Dr. Cummins.
Hola, señor. Soy el Dr. Cummins.
I'm going to be taking care of you.
Yo me haré cargo de usted.
Four for a boy...
Cuatro por un niño...
Okay, we have three shots in the abdomen.
Bien, tenemos tres disparos en el abdomen.
Five for a wedding, six for a birth...
Cinco por una boda, seis por un nacimiento...
- What's he saying? - Six for a birth.
- ¿Qué dice? - Seis por un nacimiento.
Sounds like a nursery rhyme.
Parece ser una canción de cuna.
I'm gonna have to go in and get these.
Voy a tener que ingresar para retirarlas.
Hold him down.
Sosténganlo.
Okay, here we go.
Bueno, aquí vamos.
One.
Una.
Going in for the second.
Voy por la segunda.
- Stay with me. - Five for a wedding.
- Quédese conmigo. - Cinco por una boda.
- Two.
Cinco por una boda.
Uh, uh, it's shattered.
Está fragmentada.
I'm gonna have to go in a second time.
Voy a tener que ingresar de nuevo.
- Okay, last one. - Five for a wedding...
Bueno, la última.
Wait a minute, there's something else in here.
Un momento, aquí hay algo más.
Okay, here it comes.
Bien, ya sale.
Okay.
Bien.
That's not a German bullet.
No es una bala alemana.
Eight for silver.
Ocho por la plata.
How is he?
¿Cómo se encuentra?
Not so good, ma'am.
No muy bien, señora.
Charlotte!
¡Charlotte!
I have your book.
Tengo tu libro.
Edward, that's my book. Give it back.
Edward, ese libro es mío. Devuélvemelo.
- Give it back! - Edward, stop this at once!
- ¡Devuélvelo! - Edward, ¡ya basta!
Charlotte.
Charlotte.
Please.
Por favor.
You must stop teasing your sister.
Tienes que dejar de provocar a tu hermana.
Delicious.
Delicioso.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Anais, would you mind preparing me some hot water?
Anais, ¿te importaría prepararme agua caliente?
- I'd like to take a bath. - Yes, ma'am.
- Me gustaría darme un baño. - Sí, señora.
Hey, you two better knock it off!
¡Oigan, ustedes dos, será mejor que se detengan!
- It's the elders. - Let's go down and listen.
- Son los estancieros. - Vayamos abajo a escuchar.
Yes, we need to find a solution.
Sí, tenemos que hallar una solución.
In the last three weeks, more have joined them.
En las últimas tres semanas, se les han unido más y más.
And do we know where they are?
¿Sabemos en dónde están?
They are camped between Wood Field
Están acampando entre Wood Field
and Dei's Rock.
y Deis Rock.
They claim the land belongs to them.
Alegan que la tierra les pertenece.
Has anyone looked into the validity of this claim?
¿Alguien se fijó si el reclamo es válido?
There does seem to be some validity to the claim
Parece que hay algo de validez en la demanda
that dates back 80 years,
que data de hace 80 años,
but there is nothing on record
pero no hay nada en las actas
that can't be changed in our favor.
que no pueda cambiarse a nuestro favor.
Has anyone tried to negotiate with them?
¿Alguien intentó negociar con ellos?
They're laying claim to a sizeable amount
Reclaman una cantidad considerable
of our shared lands
de nuestras tierras
and we've made them an offer to walk away.
y les hemos propuesto una oferta para que se marchen.
The offer was substantial.
La oferta fue sustancial.
They want the land.
Quieren la tierra.
That can't be allowed to happen.
No podemos permitirlo.
We all have something to lose in this room,
Todos los presentes tenemos algo que perder,
so what I'm suggesting stays in this room.
así que lo que voy a sugerir quedará en esta sala.
Charlotte, Edward, off you go. Off you go. Go, go.
Charlotte, Edward, salgan de ahí. Fuera de aquí.
The money that was offered is used to hire mercenaries
El dinero ofrecido se utilizará para contratar mercenarios
to remove them from the land.
que los erradiquen de nuestras fincas.
In my experience,
En mi experiencia,
the threat of the stick is normally enough.
la amenaza del garrote, en general, es más que suficiente.
This land is not yours.
Estas tierras no les pertenecen.
You're being told this land is not yours!
¡Se les está comunicando que estas tierras no les pertenecen!
Gather your people, get off the land!
¡Reúna a su gente, lárguense de aquí!
Here we go.
Aquí vamos.
Let's take another one.
Tomemos otra.
Caught these two trying to escape.
Atrapé a estos dos intentando escapar.
Woman had these.
La mujer tenía esto.
Old whore tried to fucking bite me with them.
La muy maldita trató de morderme con ellos.
- And did she? - Nah.
- ¿Lo logró? - No.
You think you can just waltz into my country
¿Piensas que puedes entrar bailando a mi país
with your spells and magic
con tus brujerías y conjuros
and take whatever land you fancy?
y usurpar toda la tierra que te venga en gana?
Make an example of them.
Haz un ejemplo de ellos.
A warning. His kind aren't welcome 'round here.
Una advertencia. Los de su estirpe
Make sure you bury these with her.
Cerciórate de enterrar la dentadura con ella.
You sure?
¿Está seguro?
Silver. Worth a pretty penny.
Es de plata. Vale buen dinero.
There's no worth in it. Just death.
No tiene valor. Solo muerte.
Get 'em outta my sight!
¡Quítenlos de mi vista!
Come on!
¡Vamos!
Put him there.
Colócalo allí.
Now, let's get you in a nice coat.
Ahora, te pondré un bonito abrigo.
Yeah, put that on.
Sí, póntelo.
There we go.
Ya está.
We don't want you getting cold, do we?
No queremos que pesques un resfriado, ¿no es así?
You're gonna be out here a while.
Estarás lejos por un tiempo.
to run your filthy Gypsy mouth to my captain.
las porquerías gitanas que le dijiste a mi capitán.
Let's get this on you.
Te cubriremos con esto.
Come on! Dirt soon enough.
¡Vamos! Tu tierra te espera.
Very nice.
Muy bonito.
Now time for bed.
Es hora de ir a la cama.
I'd like a room for the night.
Necesitaría rentar un cuarto por esta noche.
All guests must sign in here.
Todos los huéspedes deben firmar aquí.
State where you've been, where you're going,
Aclare dónde estuvo, a dónde se dirige
and state your business.
y la razón por la que está aquí.
Town rules.
Regla del pueblo.
Any reports of Gypsies in the area?
¿Hay reportes de gitanos en la zona?
Like I said, state your business here.
Como le dije, mencione el motivo de su visita aquí.
Other than that, food and ale are included
Por lo demás, la comida y la cerveza están incluidas
with the room.
en el valor de la habitación.
Take a seat, I'll bring you some food.
Tome asiento, le traeré algo de comer.
That didn't take very long.
No llevó mucho tiempo.
What gave me away?
¿Qué fue lo que me delató?
and you stated your profession as pathologist
y declaró ser patólogo de profesión
in the guest book,
en el libro de huéspedes,
not much.
no mucho.
Doesn't the good constable have matters to attend to?
¿Un buen agente no tiene asuntos que atender?
It's lieutenant.
Soy teniente.
I'm impressed.
Me impresiona.
I heard what happened in Gévaudan.
Escuché lo que ocurrió en Gévaudan.
I'm sorry.
Lo lamento.
How have you been?
¿Cómo ha estado?
How long will you be staying?
¿Cuánto tiempo planea quedarse?
We could use a good pathologist 'round here.
Podríamos utilizar sus habilidades
Cholera got the last one.
El cólera se llevó al último.
Well, if cholera's the only thing you have to police,
Bueno, si cólera es lo único que investiga la policía,
then you don't need a pathologist, do you?
entonces no requiere ningún patólogo, ¿verdad?
Edward!
¡Edward!
- Edward!
- ¡Edward!
Edward, come inside. Cover yourself!
Edward, ven adentro. ¡Cúbrete!
What happened?
¿Qué sucedió?
Four for a boy. Five for a wedding, six for a birth.
Cuatro por un niño. Cinco por una boda,
Seven for a curse that's buried in the Earth.
Siete por una maldición sepultada en la Tierra.
Eight for silver, nine for gold.
Ocho por la plata, nueve por el oro.
Ten for a wolf and you won't die old.
Diez por un lobo y no morirás de viejo.
Come on, Timmy, it's your go.
Ven, Timmy, te toca.
One for sorrow, two for joy,
Uno por la angustia, dos por la alegría,
three for a girl, four for a boy.
tres por una niña, cuatro por un niño.
Five for a wedding, six for a birth.
Cinco por una boda, seis por un nacimiento.
Seven for a curse that's buried in the Earth.
Siete por una maldición sepultada en la Tierra.
I've seen it.
Lo vi.
Seen what?
¿Qué viste?
Before we go any further, you must swear not to tell anyone.
Antes de continuar, deben jurar que no se lo dirán a nadie.
I mean it, your father will banish my family
En serio, si tu padre se diera cuenta
from the settlement if he finds out.
desterraría a mi familia de este pueblo.
- I swear. - We swear.
- Lo juro. - Lo juramos.
We're not supposed to be here.
No debemos estar aquí.
- The elders forbid it. - They have forbid it
- Los estancieros no nos dejan. - Lo prohibieron
ever since the night this field was on fire.
desde la noche en que se incendió la hacienda.
But since then...
Pero desde entonces...
how many of you have dreamt about the scarecrow
¿cuántos tuvieron sueños sobre el espantapájaros
and the silver teeth?
y la dentadura de plata?
Let's dig up the box of treasure.
Desenterremos el cofre del tesoro.
- You're scared. - Am not!
- Estás muerto de miedo. - ¡Claro que no!
Yes, you are.
Sí, estás aterrado.
- Scaredy-cat. - Leave him alone.
- Gallina. - Déjalo en paz.
Are you gonna dig it up?
¿Vas a desenterrarlo tú?
If you're so brave, why don't you dig it up?
Ya que eres tan valiente, ¿por qué no lo haces tú?
All right.
Está bien.
- I will. - No, Timmy, don't.
- Lo haré. - No, Timmy, no vayas.
Timmy.
Timmy.
Timmy, don't.
Timmy, no.
Run, Charlotte, run!
¡Corre, Charlotte, corre!
Charlotte, what's the matter?
Charlotte, ¿cuál es tu problema?
What is it? What's happened?
¿Qué pasa? ¿Qué sucedió?
Fetch the doctor.
Ve a buscar al doctor.
Darling, just be brave, dear.
Cariño, sé valiente, mi amor.
Here.
Aquí tienes.
It's very dark in here.
Está muy oscuro.
Yes, the light, it was hurting his eyes.
Sí, la luz le lastimaba los ojos.
Right.
Claro.
Edward has been bitten by some kind of wild animal.
A Edward lo mordió alguna especie de animal salvaje.
The wound does seem to be infected
Parece ser que la herida está infectada
and he has a fever.
y tiene fiebre.
I've treated the wound
Acabo de tratarle la mordedura
and given him something to, uh,
y le di algo para, que se tranquilice.
I shall come back in a day or two and check on him.
Regresaré dentro de uno o dos días
Thank you.
Gracias.
This way.
Por aquí.
Thank you, Doctor.
Gracias, doctor.
Edward?
¿Edward?
Eddie?
¿Eddie?
It's Edward.
Es Edward.
There's something wrong with him.
Algo no anda bien.
Stay here.
Quédate aquí.
Edward?
¿Edward?
Edward!
¡Edward!
Molière.
Molière.
Come to boast about another promotion, have you?
Viene a jactarse de otro ascenso,
There's a manor house half a day's ride from here.
Hay una casa solariega a medio día a caballo.
They've sent for me regarding their son
Mandaron buscarme porque no pueden
who's gone missing.
encontrar a su hijo.
And what's that to do with me?
¿Y qué tiene que ver conmigo?
There was a Gypsy problem that way not so long ago.
Cerca de ahí hubo una disputa con gitanos
It may be connected to what you've been looking for.
Puede que esté conectado con lo que está investigando.
Psst!
¡Pst!
What happened to Edward in the field?
¿Qué le ocurrió a Edward en el campo?
You don't remember?
¿No lo recuerdas?
What I remember was the silver teeth
Me acuerdo de los dientes de plata
and then, I woke up on the ground.
y luego, desperté en el suelo.
You used the teeth to bite Edward.
Mordiste a Edward con la dentadura.
Did you and the others tell them what happened?
¿Tú y los demás hablaron de lo que pasó?
No.
No.
We took an oath, remember?
Lo juramos, ¿recuerdas?
"And Judas asked,
"Y Judas preguntó:
'What are you willing to give me
'¿Qué estás dispuesto a darme
if I deliver him over to you?'
si te lo entrego?'.
And they counted out for him
Y le reservaron
30 pieces of silver."
30 piezas de plata".
It is the same silver that was given to Judas.
Es la misma plata que le pagaron a Judas.
Take this, you may need it.
Tómala, quizás la necesites.
Where's the silver?
¿En dónde está la plata?
It's here.
Aquí mismo.
On holy ground.
En terreno sagrado.
I saw the flames in my nightmare.
En la pesadilla vi las llamas.
We will all pay for the sins made by our elders.
Nosotros vamos a pagar los pecados
We're all going to die.
Todos vamos a morir.
Charlotte! What did Timmy want?
¡Charlotte!
Come.
Ven.
Edward!
¡Edward!
Good day, sirs.
Buenos días, señores.
Please, follow me.
Síganme, por favor.
Mr. Laurent will be with you shortly.
El Sr. Laurent vendrá en un momento.
Gentlemen. Seamus Laurent.
Caballeros.
Lieutenant Alfred Molière.
Teniente Alfred Molière.
- This is the pathologist. - John McBride.
- Él es el patólogo. - John McBride.
We have prepared guest rooms for you
Les preparamos dos dormitorios
in case you need to stay.
en caso de que tengan que quedarse.
Mr. Laurent, you sent for us
Sr. Laurent, solicitó nuestra presencia por el asunto
Yes.
Sí.
But since we sent for you,
Pero desde que los mandamos llamar,
things have gotten a lot worse.
la situación se ha vuelto mucho peor.
Jesus.
Dios.
Cause of death is consistent with attack by a wild animal.
La causa de muerte es consistente con ataque
A wild animal?
¿Animal salvaje?
Size and shape of the bite marks
El tamaño y aspecto de las mordeduras
suggest a wolf.
sugieren que fue un lobo.
Who is he?
¿Quién era?
The Adams boy.
El chico Adams.
And your son is still missing?
¿Y su hijo sigue sin aparecer?
Yes.
- Sí. - Bueno.
I'll head back to the department and file a report.
Regresaré a la jefatura
You have an attack by a wild animal.
Hay un ataque de bestia feroz.
Your boy's missing.
Su hijo no está.
I don't mean to be insensitive,
No es mi intensión parecer insensible,
but the country's in the middle of a cholera pandemic.
pero la nación está en medio de una pandemia de cólera.
Thousands are dead.
Miles han muerto.
Many towns are closing their gates.
Hay muchos pueblos que cierran sus puertas.
Trade routes heavily affected.
Rutas de comercio afectadas gravemente.
I'm sorry.
Lo lamento.
There's nothin' more I can do.
No hay nada más que pueda hacer.
No, I'd like to stay on for a few days,
No, me gustaría quedarme unos días,
if that's all right.
si le parece bien.
Let me know if your boy shows up.
Avíseme si encuentra a su hijo.
So you knew the boy.
Usted conocía a la víctima.
My son Edward and my daughter Charlotte
Mis hijos, Edward y Charlotte,
often play with the children from the settlement.
juegan a menudo con los niños del lugar.
And on the day Edward went missing,
Y cuando Edward desapareció,
what do you remember?
¿qué recuerda de ese día?
A group of them had been in the woods
Un grupo de niños había ido al bosque
with the Adams boy.
con el chico Adams.
Something had happened and Edward had been hurt.
Algo ocurrió y Edward resultó herido.
And by the time we got him back to the house,
Para el momento en que lo trajimos a casa,
he had developed a terrible fever.
ya tenía muchísima fiebre.
Something had attacked Edward in the woods.
Edward sufrió un ataque en la hacienda.
An animal.
Un animal.
He, uh... he had bite marks on his, um...
Él... tenía mordidas en su, um...
Yes, they had to have come from an animal.
Sí, que debían provenir de un animal.
Charlotte seemed to be in shock. She couldn't tell us anything.
Charlotte parecía conmocionada.
Later that evening, I went to check on him
Más tarde esa noche, lo fui a ver
but his bed was empty and he was nowhere to be found
pero su cama estaba vacía y no estaba en ninguna parte
in the house.
de la casa.
We haven't seen him since.
No lo hemos vuelto a ver desde entonces.
A few days later, the body of the Adams boy
Unos días más tarde,
was found in the woods.
se halló el cuerpo del chico Adams en el bosque.
Mr. McBride, the families in the settlement are frightened.
Sr. McBride, las familias del pueblo tienen miedo.
They are in my employ, they live on my land,
Soy su empleador, viven en mis tierras
and I am responsible for them.
y soy responsable de ellos.
They're looking to me to resolve this.
Esperan que yo resuelva este inconveniente.
May I present my wife, Isabelle.
Permítame presentarle a mi esposa, Isabelle.
This is Mr. John McBride.
Él es John McBride.
Very pleased to meet you, Mrs. Laurent.
Mucho gusto conocerla, Sra. Laurent.
I'm so sorry to hear your Edward is missing.
Lamento que Edward haya desaparecido.
- he's just run away? - No.
- que simplemente se fugara? - No.
That wouldn't be like Edward.
Edward nunca escaparía.
You see, he is a very happy child.
Verá, es un niño muy feliz.
Besides, we have searched everywhere.
Además, lo hemos buscado por todos lados.
And we are still looking for him.
Aún lo seguimos buscando.
Please help us find him.
Ayúdenos a encontrarlo, por favor.
Why, yes... uh, may I see his room?
Por qué, sí... ¿puedo ver su habitación?
Of course.
Por supuesto.
We had to clean the sheets.
Tuvimos que cambiar las sábanas.
Edward, he was, um...
Edward estaba, um...
he was unwell.
estaba enfermo.
May I see the rest of the house?
¿Puedo recorrer el resto de la casa?
Of course.
Claro que sí.
When I came down,
Cuando bajé,
this door was wide open.
esta puerta estaba abierta de par en par.
We need to board all the windows on the ground floor shut.
Es necesario tapiar las ventanas
It's just a precaution.
Solo por precaución.
Anais.
Anais.
Charlotte.
Charlotte.
John?
¿John?
Are we going to die?
¿Vamos a morir?
Of course not!
¡Claro que no!
I will not stand for such talk at the table.
No pienso soportar este tipo de charla durante la cena.
Mr. McBride is here to help us find Edward,
El Sr. McBride vino para ayudarnos a encontrar a Edward
and we can help him by maintaining our strength
y nosotros debemos apoyarlo manteniendo la entereza
and remaining steadfast.
y siempre inquebrantables.
Now, eat, please.
Ahora, coman, por favor.
McBride?
¿McBride?
Seamus, fetch a rifle.
Seamus, traiga su rifle.
What kind of animal tries to break into houses?
¿Qué clase de animal intenta ingresar a las casas?
There are some things I'm going to need from you.
Voy a necesitar que consiga unas cosas.
What's happening here?
¿Qué sucede aquí?
Can't be sure until I set up a hunting ground.
No lo sabré hasta que establezca un coto de caza.
You're gonna hunt it?
¿Lo va a cazar?
I'll need to gather the elders and tell them of your plans.
Me reuniré con los estancieros para contarles su plan.
We own all the land in this region.
Poseemos todas las tierras de la región.
Make sure they travel under armed guard.
Cerciórese de que viajen con guardias armados.
Gentlemen, you're all aware of the unfortunate circumstances
Caballeros, ya están al tanto de las circunstancias
that have brought us here this evening,
desafortunadas que nos congregaron esta noche,
the killing of the local child
el asesinato de un muchacho del pueblo
and the disappearance of my own son, Edward.
y la desaparición de mi hijo, Edward.
Mr. John McBride has kindly offered
El Sr. McBride tuvo la amabilidad de ofrecerse
to help capture the animal that killed the Adams boy.
para ayudar a capturar a la fiera que mató al chico Adams.
You are sure that this is some kind of animal,
¿Está seguro de que fue un animal
not the work of a madman?
y no la obra de algún desquiciado?
After examining the body,
Luego de examinar el cuerpo,
I concluded that the cause of death
llegué a la conclusión de que la causa de muerte
had been consistent with an animal bite.
era consistente con mordedura de animal.
What kind of an animal are we talking about?
¿De que tipo de bestia estamos hablando?
Wolf.
Lobo.
You're a pathologist.
Usted es patólogo.
That's correct.
Sí, correcto.
What does that mean, exactly?
¿Qué significa exactamente?
Our body speaks even after our death.
Los cuerpos hablan incluso después del fallecimiento.
I listen.
Yo los escucho.
Isn't it a job for hunters?
¿No es un trabajo para cazadores?
I'm sure we've all read about the Beast of Gévaudan,
Seguramente leyeron sobre la Bestia de Gévaudan
perhaps heard the stories.
o tal vez hayan escuchado historias.
You see, I was stationed there
Verán, me destacaron allí
during the troubles with the army.
durante el conflicto armado.
You think what happened in Gévaudan is happening here?
¿Cree que lo que ocurrió en Gévaudan está pasando aquí?
It might very well be.
Es muy probable que sí.
Then, isn't this a job for the army?
Entonces, ¿no es obligación del ejército?
Unfortunately, the army can... will...
Por desgracia, al ejército se lo puede... se lo convocará
only be deployed if there is confirmation
exclusivamente, si hay confirmación,
that the same thing is happening here as in Gévaudan.
de que aquí ocurre lo mismo
Are you suggesting that we stay inside our house
¿Nos sugiere que no salgamos de nuestras casas
and board the windows shut?
y que tapiemos las ventanas?
I would strongly advise it.
Lo aconsejaría firmemente.
No one should be out in the field
Nadie debería estar en el campo
until that madman is caught.
hasta que apresen al demente.
There's no use complaining.
No tiene sentido quejarse.
We drew the short straws.
Lo echamos a la suerte y perdimos.
We get this done, we get ourselves home,
Hacemos el trabajo y regresamos a casa,
all right?
¿está bien?
Jakob, you take the far side.
Jakob, tú ve por allí.
We'll work inwards till we meet in the middle.
Nosotros iremos hacia el centro hasta encontrarnos en el medio.
Keep your eyes peeled. Stay in sight.
Estén alerta.
All right?
¿Bien?
Calum?
¿Calum?
Calum!
¡Calum!
Jakob?
¿Jakob?
Run!
¡Corre!
Help!
¡Auxilio!
Somebody help!
¡Alguien que me ayude!
This is all we found.
Esto es lo único que encontramos.
Anne-Marie was working the fields with Calum and Jakob.
Anne-Marie estaba trabajando el campo con Calum y Jakob.
She made it back to the settlement and raised the alarm.
Logró regresar al pueblo y dio la alarma.
We came back here and...
Nosotros volvimos hasta aquí y...
no Calum and no Jakob.
no hallamos ni a Calum ni a Jakob.
Did the girl see what attacked them?
¿La chica pudo ver qué los atacó?
Well... she's in shock.
Bueno... está conmocionada.
What... what she says makes no sense.
Lo que... lo que dice no tiene sentido.
What did she say?
¿Qué fue lo que dijo?
She said it was a dragon.
Dijo que era un dragón.
She's in a bad way, she... she's lost a lot of blood.
Está bastante mal, ella... perdió mucha sangre.
She was bitten?
¿La mordió?
Where is she?
¿En dónde está?
She... she was just here.
Ella... estaba justo aquí.
Everyone must leave.
Se tendrán que ir todos.
We can't protect them in the field or in the village.
No podemos protegerlos ni en el bosque ni en el pueblo.
It's no longer safe here.
Aquí ya no es seguro.
- And go where? - Take them to the church,
¿A dónde irán?
barricade the door shut.
y que parapeten la puerta.
Food and water can be fetched for,
Para ir en busca de agua o alimentos,
but under armed escort only.
exclusivamente con escolta armada.
It is imperative that we limit this exposure.
Es indispensable limitar la exposición.
Exposure?
¿La exposición?
- Exposure to what? - Seamus,
¿Exposición a qué?
Water, I need water.
Agua, necesito agua.
Sorry.
Disculpe.
Oh, me neither.
Yo tampoco.
Drink?
¿Un trago?
Yes.
Sí.
Who's Edith?
¿Quién es Edith?
My wife.
Mi esposa.
Do you have children?
¿Tiene hijos?
Seems a long time ago now.
Parece que transcurrió una eternidad.
Are they no longer with you?
¿Ya no están con usted?
We'd been stationed to Gévaudan.
Estábamos en Gévaudan por mi trabajo.
They were plagued by a wolf.
Los asediaba un lobo.
Two people had been killed in the first week,
Dos personas murieron la primera semana,
six the following.
seis la siguiente.
That's when the army had been drafted in.
Por eso enviaron al ejército.
There was talk that the wolf was a curse,
Había habladurías de que el lobo era una maldición
and if people need to know.
y si la gente tenía que saberlo.
The first time I saw it,
La primera vez que lo vi
it was covered in fresh blood,
estaba cubierto de sangre fresca,
just outside our village.
fue en las afueras del pueblo.
By the time I got back there, it was... too late.
Cuando regresé ya era... demasiado tarde.
Thirteen people had been killed by the beast.
Había trece personas despedazadas por la bestia.
My wife and daughter were among them.
Mi hija y esposa estaban entre ellas.
I'm so sorry.
Lo lamento.
Did they ever catch this wolf?
¿Atraparon a la fiera?
Shortly after that,
No mucho después,
a band of traveling gypsies came to Gévaudan.
un grupo de gitanos nómades llegó a Gévaudan.
They said the curse had had its revenge
Dijeron que la maldición ya había cobrado su venganza
and was to be contained in gypsy silver.
y había que contenerla en plata gitana.
They then traveled northwest,
Después partieron con rumbo al noroeste,
but the trail went cold in Le Malzieu.
pero el rastro se esfumó en Le Malzieu.
Well, the gypsies had a claim on my husband's land.
Bueno, los gitanos tenían derecho a reclamar
My husband and the elders...
Mi marido y los estancieros...
That's enough!
¡Ya basta!
That's enough.
Suficiente.
I want no more talk of curses.
No quiero escuchar nada más acerca de brujerías.
We've locked everybody in a church,
Parapetamos a todo el mundo en la iglesia
and I have nobody working the fields.
y no tengo a nadie trabajando los campos.
If you're here to help, then please help.
Si vino para ayudarnos, por favor, hágalo.
I just want this beast or this wolf or whatever it is
Lo único que quiero es capturar y sacrificar
captured and killed.
a ese lobo o lo que sea.
Tomorrow I will set the traps.
Mañana pondré las trampas.
What in God's name is it?
¿Qué demonios es eso?
Gentlemen, I must warn you,
Caballeros, debo advertirles
this won't be easy.
que esto no será sencillo.
- Oh, Jesus. - Oh, my God.
Dios.
- It's Anne-Marie. - Don't touch it!
- Es Anne-Marie. - ¡No la toque!
They never come back the same.
Jamás vuelven a ser los que eran.
It's the kindest thing we can do for her now, Saul.
Es lo más humano que se puede hacer, Saul.
I've known her since she was a baby.
La conozco desde que era bebé.
Saul.
Saul.
- Saul!
- ¡Saul!
Saul!
¡Saul!
Saul, shoot her!
¡Saul, dispárele!
Do it now!
¡Ahora mismo!
Is this a fate that has befallen my son?
¿Este es el destino que le tocó a mi hijo?
Isabelle must never know about this, I beg you.
Isabelle no tiene que enterarse de nada, se lo suplico.
What else doesn't she know about?
¿De qué otra situación no está enterada?
Do you dream much, Seamus?
¿Tiene muchos sueños, Seamus?
The land of Gévaudan had been cursed.
Las tierras de Gévaudan tenían un maleficio.
At night, everyone had the same dream.
Por las noches, todos sus habitantes
What?
¿Qué?
The woman buried in the field.
La mujer que está enterrada en el bosque.
Woman... I don't know what you're talking about.
Mujer... No sé de qué me está hablando.
She cursed the land.
Ella maldijo la tierra.
That's absurd.
Qué ridiculez.
Is what you just saw absurd?
¿Lo que acaba de ver es ridículo?
The dreams, the beast.
Los sueños, la bestia.
You were cursed, and it started with Edward.
Los embrujaron, y comenzó con Edward.
Edward? Edward had nothing to do with this.
¿Edward?
He will kill and keep on killing.
Volverá a matar y va a seguir.
- Edward is innocent. - Anyone who survives an attack
- Edward es inocente. - El que sobrevive al ataque
will change until the curse has had its revenge.
se transforma hasta que el hechizo haya
Revenge? I am the one seeking revenge
¿Venganza?
for what this thing has done to my family!
por lo que le han hecho a mi familia!
I started this, so I will finish it.
Yo originé el problema y lo voy a terminar.
I will hunt it myself and put an end to it once and for all.
Le daré caza y acabaré con él de una vez por todas.
Now you burn this thing...
Ahora, incineren al engendro...
...whatever it is.
o como sea que se llame.
Get the torch.
Traigan la antorcha.
Please don't leave us, Nana.
No te vayas, Nana, por favor.
Go on, Charlotte.
Sé fuerte, Charlotte.
Isabelle...
Isabelle...
Who is the woman buried in the field?
¿Quién es la mujer que está sepultada en el bosque?
It's the only trophy that's kept locked in a drawer
Es el único trofeo que decidió ocultar
and not displayed on the wall.
en lugar de exhibirlo en la pared.
We must find what was buried.
Debemos encontrar lo que había enterrado.
We've all dreamt of the silver that has cursed this land.
Todos tuvimos sueños sobre la plata que embrujó las fincas.
On the body of Timmy, I found a page torn from the Bible.
En el cuerpo de Timmy encontré
He knew something about the silver,
Él sabía algo acerca de la plata
"As silver is melted in the furnace,
"Como la plata que se funde por obra del fuego,
so will you be melted in its midst;
ustedes también por culpa de ella;
and you shall know that I, the Lord,
y se enterarán de que yo, el Señor,
have poured out My fury upon you."
he vertido mi furia sobre ustedes".
Ezekiel 22:22.
Ezequiel 22:22.
Charlotte...
Charlotte...
is there anything you can tell us?
¿hay algo que nos puedas decir?
Anything at all?
¿Cualquier detalle?
"And Judas asked, 'What are you willing to give me
"Y Judas preguntó: '¿Qué estás dispuesto a darme
if I deliver Him over to you?'
si te lo entrego?'.
So they counted out for him 30 pieces of silver."
Y le reservaron 30 piezas de plata".
The silver from the dream.
La plata del sueño.
You believe it was the same silver given to Judas.
Crees que es la misma plata que le dieron a Judas.
Where is the silver?
¿En dónde está esa plata?
McBride, open the door!
¡Soy McBride, abran la puerta!
We've all prayed for your safety.
Hemos rezado por su seguridad.
Some of the men have joined Seamus
Algunos de los hombres se unieron a la travesía
to go and hunt the beast.
de Seamus para cazar a la bestia.
We cannot control what Seamus
No podemos controlar lo que Seamus
is doing or has done.
esté haciendo ni lo que hizo.
I believe there is a way to stop this.
Creo que hay una forma de detener esta locura.
Charlotte...
Charlotte...
where is it?
¿en dónde está?
Saul, send word to Molière.
Saul, envíele un mensaje a Molière.
The army must be deployed immediately.
El ejército debe acudir de inmediato.
And, Saul, I need a blacksmith.
Y, Saul, necesito un herrero.
We'll try again tomorrow at first light.
Lo intentaremos de nuevo mañana al amanecer.
Isabelle?
¿Isabelle?
Have you seen my wife?
¿Has visto a mi esposa?
I'm sorry, sir.
Discúlpeme, señor.
What's the matter with you, are you sick?
¿Qué te ocurre? ¿Estás enferma?
No, I'm fine.
No, estoy bien.
Go and clean yourself up.
Ve a limpiarte.
One hundred.
Cien.
Two hundred.
Doscientos.
Three hundred.
Trescientos.
Four hundred.
Cuatrocientos.
Five hundred.
Quinientos.
Is anyone missing?
¿Falta alguien?
Everybody's here.
Todos estamos presentes.
What is it?
¿Qué sucede?
Where is the maid?
¿Dónde está la criada?
She's in the kitchen, why?
En la cocina, ¿por qué pregunta?
I think you should leave here.
Creo que debería irse de aquí.
Charlotte, darling, please go to your room.
Charlotte, mi amor, sube a tu habitación, por favor.
- Tomorrow. - No, Seamus.
- Mañana. - No, Seamus.
We need John's help.
Necesitamos la ayuda de John.
We'll hunt again at first light
Mañana iremos a cazarlo al amanecer
and put an end to all this.
y le pondré fin a todo esto.
And come back empty-handed
Y regresará con las manos vacías igual que hoy.
Like all the weeks the army tried
Igual que todas las semanas que el ejército intentó atrapar
to hunt the Beast of Gévaudan.
a la Bestia de Gévaudan.
It's you it wants, Seamus.
Lo busca a usted, Seamus.
You and your kin.
A usted y a su familia.
Dead or chains makes no difference.
Muertos o apresados no le interesa.
You don't have to go hunt for it,
No hace falta que le dé caza,
because it will hunt you for what you've done.
porque lo va a venir a buscar por lo que hizo.
What I did I did for my family.
Lo que hice lo hice por mi familia.
The gypsies, they had a claim to the land, didn't they?
Los gitanos tenían derecho a reclamar la tierra, ¿no es así?
- It was my land. - And you stole it from them!
- Es mía. - ¡Porque usted se la robó!
- And I lost my son! - Now you know the cost of greed.
¡Y perdí a mi hijo!
My wife and child paid the price because of men like you!
¡Mi esposa e hija pagaron el precio por hombres como usted!
Please, please.
Por favor, por favor.
I just want to find my Edward.
Solo quiero encontrar a mi Edward.
Yes.
Sí.
Why don't you ask your husband where he is?
¿Por qué no le pregunta a su esposo dónde está?
Get out.
Váyase.
You know, Seamus, all this time
Sabe una cosa, Seamus, todo el tiempo pensé que rastreaba
I thought I was tracking the beast that took my family.
a la fiera que me había arrebatado a mi familia.
But now I realize I got it all wrong.
Pero ahora me doy cuenta de que estaba equivocado.
I'm just the caretaker,
Yo solo me ocupo,
making sure it all gets put back in the box
me aseguro de que todo regrese a su lugar
before any more innocent people are killed.
antes de que más inocentes paguen con sus vidas.
I'm staying here until the army arrives.
Me quedaré hasta que llegue el ejército.
I miss Edward.
Extraño a Edward.
Can you stay with me here tonight?
¿Te quedas aquí conmigo esta noche?
Of course, darling.
Claro que sí, cariño.
Anais?
¿Anais?
Have you seen Seamus?
¿Ha visto a Seamus?
Isabelle!
¡Isabelle!
Charlotte!
¡Charlotte!
Charlotte, Isabelle!
¡Charlotte, Isabelle!
Isabelle!
¡Isabelle!
Seamus!
¡Seamus!
It's Seamus, he's gone outside.
Es Seamus, acaba de salir.
He's out...
Está fuera...
Find Charlotte.
Busque a Charlotte.
The house is on fire, go!
La casa se está incendiando, ¡vaya!
Seamus!
¡Seamus!
Charlotte.
Charlotte.
Charlotte, we must leave the house.
Charlotte, tenemos que salir de la casa.
Seamus!
¡Seamus!
Seamus.
Seamus.
It was Anais.
Era Anais.
I shot it.
Le disparé.
I see the flames every night, John.
Veo las llamas todas las noches, John.
I was bitten.
Me mordió.
I'll change.
Me voy a transformar.
Tell Isabelle and Charlotte
Diles a Isabelle y a Charlotte que lo lamento mucho.
No, no, wait, wait!
¡No, no, espere, espere!
Come on!
¡Vengan!
Wait, where's Seamus?
Un momento, ¿dónde está Seamus?
We have to get to the church.
Tenemos que huir a la iglesia.
It's the only safe place. Let's go.
Es el único lugar seguro.
Come on!
¡Vengan!
Let's go!
¡Vamos!
Come, come, come.
Vengan, vengan, vengan.
Nana?
¿Nana?
Get down, get down.
Ocúltense, al suelo.
Stay still, stay still.
Quédese quieta, no se mueva.
Nana?
¿Nana?
Charlotte, you must be quiet.
Charlotte, haz silencio.
Stay right there.
Quédense aquí.
Silver.
Plata.
Get up, get up!
¡Levántense, levántense!
Come on, move, go!
¡Vamos, muévanse, vengan!
Come.
Vamos.
Stay behind me and move towards the church.
Permanezcan detrás de mí y diríjanse a la iglesia.
Move, go, go.
Muévanse, vamos, vamos.
- Let us in! - Open the door!
- ¡Déjennos entrar! - ¡Abran la puerta!
Open the door!
¡Abran la puerta!
Close the door.
Ciérrala.
What's happened?
¿Qué sucedió?
And Seamus?
¿Y Seamus?
He didn't make it.
No logró sobrevivir.
We barely made it here.
Por poco y no llegamos.
It stalked us the whole way.
Nos acechó todo el camino.
Were you all that is left?
¿Solo sobrevivieron ustedes?
Aye.
Sí.
So what do we do now?
¿Qué hacemos ahora?
- We wait. - Wait?
- Esperar. - ¿Esperar?
Wait for what?
¿Esperar qué?
No, no, I'm tired of waiting,
No, no, estoy harto de esperar,
hiding.
de esconderme.
We're like sheep.
Parecemos ovejas.
If you're telling me the thing that killed my son
Si afirma que el engendro que asesinó a mi hijo
is just outside those doors, I say,
se encuentra del otro lado de la puerta, yo digo,
I say we go outside and we kill it.
digo que tenemos que salir a matarlo.
You go out those doors and you will be dead.
Si traspasa esa puerta, fenecerá.
How come you made it here? You're not dead.
¿Cómo hizo para venir hasta aquí?
I have something it's afraid of.
Tengo algo que él teme.
What?
¿Qué?
I have the silver bullet.
Mis balas son de plata.
But we have to wait for daylight,
Pero debemos esperar a que salga el sol,
draw it into the open and have a clean shot.
sacarlo de su escondite y asestarle un tiro limpio.
That is our only hope.
Esa es la única esperanza.
We got word to Molière.
Recibimos noticias de Molière.
The army will be here by morning.
El ejército estará aquí en la mañana.
- That's good. - Now rest.
Qué bien.
We've got a long night ahead of us.
Tenemos una noche larga por delante.
I believe this belonged to your boy.
Creo que le pertenecía a su hijo.
What happened to Seamus?
¿Qué le sucedió a Seamus?
It was Anais.
Fue Anais.
He was badly wounded when I got to him.
Estaba muy malherido cuando lo encontré.
He told me to tell you and Charlotte...
Me pidió que les dijera a usted y a Charlotte...
that he was sorry.
que lo sentía.
Is Edward lost to this nightmare?
¿Perdimos a Edward en esta pesadilla?
I can't say.
No lo sé.
The sins of my people have soiled.
Los pecados de mi gente fueron condenables.
But now I come to you as a mother,
Pero ahora, me dirijo a Ti como madre,
aching the weight of my grief, please.
sufriendo el peso de mi dolor, te suplico.
Anything I can give, any path,
Lo que sea que pueda dar, cualquier manera,
please show me, I beg you.
por favor, te ruego que me guíes.
Show us mercy, if there is any hope, please show me.
Ten piedad de nosotros, si existe esperanza,
I beg you, Lord, show us mercy.
Te imploro misericordia, Señor.
Please don't leave us, don't go!
Por favor, ¡no nos abandones, no te vayas!
Please, Mother!
¡Madre, por favor!
Edward.
Edward.
Mother, please, please, come get me!
¡Madre, te lo pido, por favor, ven por mí!
Mother!
¡Madre!
Edward.
Edward.
Edward, I'm coming.
Edward, ahí voy.
Isabelle!
¡Isabelle!
No!
¡No!
Mother!
¡Madre!
Get back!
¡Aléjense!
Enough!
¡Basta!
- Isabelle. - Edward.
- Isabelle. - Edward.
Move out of the way.
Quítese de en medio.
No.
No.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
Picked them up off the church floor.
Las levanté del suelo en la iglesia.
He doesn't remember anything.
No recuerda nada.
Edward.
Edward.
Son.
Hijo.
You and your sister are going to come and live with me now.
Tú y tu hermana van a venir a vivir conmigo
All right?
¿Está bien?
None of this was your fault, son.
Nada de lo ocurrido fue tu culpa, hijo.
All right.
Muy bien.
Up you go.
Vamos, arriba.
Charlotte.
Charlotte.
It's time.
Ya es hora.